What we are looking at now
is the lobby footage of Xinmai Hotel.
The deceased, Li Ting,
left on May 6
and didn't return until May 13.
This is the footage of his return.
Okay, next.
At 3:22 PM,
Li Ting returned to his room.
At this moment,
the cleaner was cleaning the room.
Li Ting asked the waiter to leave shortly after he went in.
This is the footage of him leaving.
Okay, next one.
After the waiter left,
at 4:14 PM,
he ordered a box of convenience food via delivery
and successfully signed for it.
After the deliveryman left,
he never stepped out of the room again.
No one else came during this period.
Until this morning,
which is May 26th at 8:03 AM,
when the waiter came to clean the room,
opened the door with a master key,
and found the deceased.
No one went in or out.
Could there be a problem with the surveillance video?
The video has been authenticated.
There are no signs of tampering.
Good job, Fang.
Serve the people.
Could it be an accident?
Cheng Mo and I did a simulation analysis of the scene.
There's definitely something wrong with the state of the body.
Shao.
When will the autopsy report be ready?
The body is highly decomposed.
Plus, the temperature at the crime scene
was kept too low by the AC.
I can't give an accurate time of death report right now.
As soon as possible.
Okay.
Xiao Bai.
Do you have any new findings on your end?
The deceased's parents passed away early.
He has no relatives
or friends in Mancheng.
As a freelance writer,
the only person he interacts with
is the magazine editor.
The editor did contact him a few times,
but thought he was in a creative retreat
and didn't suspect anything.
Also, his wife, Lu Chen,
separated from him half a year ago due to marital discord,
went back to her hometown in Luocheng,
and has been preparing for a divorce.
Li Ting went back to Luocheng on May 6th to discuss the divorce
and returned alone on the 13th.
Lu Chen obviously has an alibi.
They discussed divorce for a week.
Have Lu Chen come to the station as soon as possible.
I've already notified him.
He'll be here first thing tomorrow morning.
Strange.
What's strange?
No one entered or left the room.
Yet the victim was murdered.
This is a locked-room murder.
The waiter who found the deceased.
Where is the statement?
Oh.
She was terrified
and didn't have time to make a statement.
But I've already informed her.
She will be here soon.
Sister.
Sister Liu, don't be nervous.
We just want to ask you a few questions.
Just cooperate with the investigation.
Okay, I'll cooperate.
Li Ting, as a long-term tenant,
didn't leave his room for two weeks.
Didn't you want to go in and check?
We didn't go in.
He didn't leave his room for a while before.
The manager wanted to go in and check.
But he yelled at him.
And complained about us.
If we hadn't smelled the odor this time,
we wouldn't have gone in.
From May 13th to today,
have you noticed anything unusual?
Unusual?
A few days ago,
the staff break room on the first floor
smelled really bad.
I didn't pay much attention to it.
Now that I think about it,
it might have come from the second floor.
Which room?
I mean the staff break room.
Oh.
Right below 208.
Room 108.
Because it used to be the kitchen.
Later,
it was converted into a staff break room.
Why didn't you report the bad smell?
Xiao Zhao quit, didn't she?
She was in charge of the second floor.
I was in charge of the first floor and the staff break room.
Now that she's gone,
how can I manage?
Do you know why she quit?
I get angry just talking about it.
Isn't it because of Mr. Li in Room 208?
He insisted that Xiao Zhao stole his watch.
Zhao,
what's the rush?
The guest in 208 is saying I stole things again.
Still about that?
Yeah, it never ends.
I didn't steal anything.
It's endless.
Keep your voice down.
Why should I?
Is it fair to be treated like this?
Don't stoop to his level.
How can I not?
I'm really quitting.
Don't try to stop me.
Zhao.
Save your breath.
She was so angry.
She packed her bags and left that night.
Do you remember which day it was?
Yes.
Around 9 p.m. on the 13th.
Isn't that Zhao?
Zhao!
This kid...
She was in a hurry.
I called her several times, but she ignored me.
Young people nowadays just leave on a whim.
She must have felt wronged.
You guys order.
I'll do it.
I've been watching the surveillance footage all day.
My eyes are getting blurry,
but I still haven't found any useful clues.
As for this case,
it's most likely an accident.
Thank you for your hard work.
How about this?
Let's wait for my autopsy report first.
There might be other discoveries.
So when will your autopsy report be ready?
I promise it will be as soon as possible.
Two of these.
Thank you.
Hurry up, ma'am.
I'm starving. Thank you.
Got it.
Thank you.
Sit down. Hurry up and sit.
Sister.
Manager Feng sent over the information about the temporary cleaner.
Look.
I know her.
Isn't she the cleaner
who cleaned his room on the 13th?
Yes, that's her.
She even had an argument with the deceased.
According to Liu Ying,
it was because the deceased accused her of stealing that day.
That's right.
Then she must be the murderer.
Seeking revenge after being framed by the deceased.
Impossible.
I saw it very clearly on the surveillance.
The deceased was still alive when she left.
Then she must have entered the room using other methods.
What method?
For example,
she dropped a rope from the roof
and swung into the window.
This...
Are you out of your mind?
Have you been watching too many movies?
Female agent? Swinging in?
Then I'm the Monkey King.
Unbelievable.
Don't laugh at me.
She's right.
What?
Mr. Cheng thinks she's an agent too.
Not exactly.
There are no signs of forced entry on the window.
Then why did you say she's right?
I meant
the murderer definitely entered and exited the room in another way.
Could there be a secret passage?
She really is the talent you talked about.
Lao Zhang.
Why is your place leaking water again?
No way.
I just fixed it.
Go look, it's right in your kitchen.
It's so weird.
Every time my water pipe leaks,
how come you discover it before me?
Nonsense, I can't do business like this.
Fix it quickly.
Don't delay my business.
Come here.
I know.
A few days ago,
the staff lounge on the first floor
had a foul smell.
I didn't pay much attention to it then.
Now that I think about it,
it might have come from the second floor.
I know.
Cheng Mo.
Remember to get me an invoice.
What's wrong with him?
Should we turn on the light first?
What are you looking for?
Do you remember Liu Ying's statement?
I remember.
She said when she was in the lounge,
she smelled something rotten.
The essence of a smell is tiny fragments of matter.
These fragments slowly diffuse,
and pass through here.
They continue to move in the air,
and finally reach the next floor.
So here is the question.
After Li Ting decayed,
how did these fragments float downstairs?
It seems Xiaobai was right.
There must be a secret passage here.
What are you doing?
Dong Shan, call the police quickly!
No need.
Zhuang Lan, Accident Investigation Team.
We need a secondary investigation into the case.
Sorry,
Officer Zhuang Lan.
You see it's so dark,
and the lights aren't on.
We thought a thief had broken in.
Yes.
I understand.
But before the case is closed,
you can't just enter here freely.
Okay.
Understood.
Let's go, Dong Shan.
Call us anytime if you need anything.
This is the place.
Hey, Fang.
Major discovery.
San,
about what I asked you the other day,
is it true?
Okay.
Thank you.
Alright.
Yeah, I got it.